mercariapp.com 2019-05-02

# Mercari Help Center

Privacy policy.

In this policy, we, Mercari Inc., headquartered in Palo Alto, California, inform you about our personal data collection and use practices relating to your use of Mercari's mobile and website consumer-to-consumer marketplace service. It does not cover other data collection or processing by Mercari or data that other companies collect or sites or services that are linked from our service.

### Changes

Carefully review this policy. We will amend it from time to time as our technology, services, features and business models change, so you should review our current privacy policy every time you use our service.  Our privacy practices are summarized in our Privacy Notice.

### Children

Children under 18 are not allowed to use the Mercari service.

### Account data

When you sign up for our service, you actively provide us with account registration information that you can access and update within the Mercari app or website at any time, including:

  * Contact information, such as your name, address, phone, and email
  * Financial information, such as bank account and/or credit card numbers
  * Detailed personal information such as your date of birth or tax identification number

We use your email address to communicate with you about transactions, new services and other topics we believe are of interest to you. We use your mailing address for delivery of items you purchase through our service. We collect your credit card or other payment card information for payment processing purposes and your bank account information to post deposits when you sell items through our service. We collect social network info for login and authentication purposes.

When we are required by applicable law, we collect additional information from you such as your social security number or tax identification number or date of birth, and we may request you to provide us with such information. You consent to promptly comply with such request from us if you wish to continue using the service. We use this additional information, in combination with other information we may collect from you such as information about your government-issued identification, for identity verification and fraud prevention purposes, or any other purposes necessary to comply with applicable law.

We may also update your registration information, for example, if you provide a new email or mailing address on your account.

### Usage data

When you use the Mercari service, we process and deliver to you and other users of our service information about your Mercari transactions, such as information about items that you post for sale through our service and messages exchanged with other Mercari users. In this context, we receive information about your device, software, who you communicate with, message content, locations and our access logs, which includes IP address, device ID, your actions within our service and language settings.

Our browser-based app version and website also places cookies as necessary to provide functionality to you. We associate usage data with your device and your personal account. We process usage information to deliver, improve and optimize our Mercari service, to protect you, us and other users from actual or potential fraud and misuse, and to determine what information, features, promotional information and other services you need or may be interested in.

The information Mercari collects may be sent to us by your computer, mobile phone or other access device. The information includes, but is not limited to, the following: data about the pages you access, computer IP address, device ID or unique identifier, device type, geo-location information, computer and connection information, mobile network information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the sites, referral URL, ad data, and standard web log data and other information

### Third party sources

We may obtain information about you from third parties such as identity verification services.

We may combine your usage data with information we collect from other companies such as Google Analytics to customize and improve your user experience. Google Analytics collects information regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources ( For more information, please visit [https://web.archive.org/web/20190418161136/https://policies.google.com/privacy/partners](https://policies.google.com/privacy/partners).)

You may choose to provide us with access to certain personal information stored by third parties such as social media sites (e.g., Facebook [https://web.archive.org/web/20190418161136/https://www.facebook.com/policy.php](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)). The information we may receive varies by site and is controlled by that site. By associating an account managed by a third party with your Mercari account and authorizing Mercari to have access to this information, you agree that we may collect, store and use this information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Cookie Statement

The cookies we use on our browser-based app and website do not hold any personal information about you. Where personally identifiable information is required to be gathered, the need for this information will be clearly communicated before you choose to provide the information.

Many Internet browsers allow you to adjust your cookie preferences or delete existing cookies. If you set your browser to reject cookies, you should be aware that certain browser-based app or website features, promotions or services may not be available to you or may not function correctly.

Certain Internet browsers may enable you to set "do not track" preferences, to limit the collection of personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services. Mercari’s systems do not respond to Internet browser "do not track" signals or similar mechanisms.

### Data retention and access

You can review and edit your personal information at any time by logging in to your account and reviewing your account settings. You can also close your account.

We retain account and usage data as long as required by applicable law. We may retain personal information from your account to collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, complete investigations, prevent fraud, enforce our Terms of Service User Agreement, or take other actions as required or permitted by law.

If you close your Mercari account we will inactivate the account within less than 10 business days. Please keep in mind that others can retain messages and content that you have sent them or posted publicly before you closed your account and we keep deactivated account information for a certain time period in our archives.

Disclosures, sharing

We do not disclose your individual account or usage data to third parties, except:

  * with your consent or at your direction.
  * as necessary to collect payment.
  * to service or process a product or service requested by you or otherwise provide our service to you.
  * to enable service providers under contract to facilitate operations, such as fraud prevention & risk management, bill collection, marketing, customer service and technology services.
  * as necessary to resolve a problem between Mercari users or with third parties.
  * with affiliated and unaffiliated service providers in the United States and abroad that help us deliver, analyze, improve and manage our service, subject to confidentiality agreements.
  * as required by law or to assert or protect legal rights.
  * to comply with anti-money laundering and counter-terrorist financing verification requirements.
  * as necessary to protect you, other users, us or third parties from actual or potential harm, including fraud, data security or confidentiality breaches, other liability, or where someone's physical safety seems at risk.
  * to maintain or service your account.
  * in connection with a proposed or actual sale or reorganization of our company, divisions or assets, subject to the acquirer accepting the commitments made in this policy and in compliance with applicable law.
  * as described in our Privacy Notice.
  * as otherwise permitted by law.

Note that when you publicly post content, such as sales listings, that content is visible and available to third parties.

### Security

We take required steps to protect your account information and account messages and to protect against data loss, misuse and unauthorized access. However, no internet transmission is ever completely secure or error-free. In particular, messages sent through the Mercari service are not encrypted.

It is your responsibility to control access to your device, including keeping your login information confidential and not sharing it with anyone. It is also your responsibility to notify Mercari if you believe the security of the information in the Mercari app or your Mercari account has been compromised.

### Your choices

We respect your communication preferences. If you no longer wish to receive notifications via our application, you can adjust your preferences by visiting the settings page of the application.

If we send marketing messages, you can opt out by changing the settings in your Mercari profile account or by contacting us or by following the directions that may be provided within the communication..  Note that if you opt out, we may still send you non-marketing messages, such as messages about your account or products and services you have requested.

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes. We may combine your usage information with information we collect from other companies and use it to improve and personalize your Mercari experience. Mercari may use this information for its own marketing purpose.

Questions, Requests, Rights

If you have any questions or requests, please contact us in our Help Center within the mobile app or website. Please reference “Privacy Policy” in the subject line of your inquiry. You may access information that we have about you and correct such information and request the deletion of your personal data in accordance with applicable law.

  * Updated May 25, 2018
  * Updated November 25, 2017
  * Updated February 28, 2017
  * Updated September 12, 2016
  * Updated May 18, 2016
  * Updated July 16, 2015
  * Updated December 21, 2014
  * Established July 11, 2014
